[ Music ]
［ 音乐 ］
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
&gt;&gt; Hello. Welcome everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好 非常欢迎
My name is Gaurav.
我是 Gaurav
And today we are going to talk
今天要向大家介绍的主题是
about machine learning.
机器学习
Last year, we launched Core ML.
去年我们发布了 Core ML
And the response from
从各位开发人员处
developers, from you guys have
得到的反馈
been tremendous.
非同凡响
We are just amazed by the apps
你们开发的 App
you have made, the [inaudible]
令人惊叹
phenomenal.
效果也非常出众
thank you.
所以 首先让我对大家表示感谢
Thank you for embracing Core ML.
谢谢你们信任 Core ML
And we are -- we love seeing so
我们非常高兴看到
many of you using it and giving
这么多开发人员
intelligent features to our
使用 Core ML
users.
并给用户带来智能体验
We are in this together.
因为我们是共进退的
Thank you.
感谢大家
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
It's an applause for the
这是给所有开发人员的掌声
Okay. So if you recall, Core ML
好 如果你还有印象
gives you an easy way to
Core ML 让你可以轻松
integrate an ML model in the
将机器学习模型
app.
应用于你的 App 中
The idea is very simple.
整个过程非常简单
You get an ML model, you drag
找到一个机器学习模型
and drop in Xcode, and with just
拖拽到 Xcode 中
three lines of code, you can run
然后仅添加三行代码
state-of-the-art ML model with
你就可以实时运行
millions of parameters and
最先进的机器学习模型
billions of calculations in real
以及其中几百万个参数
time.
和几十亿次计算
It's just amazing.
真是令人惊叹
And you give -- your users get
你的用户可以
real time machine learning as
实时体验机器学习
well as privacy-friendly machine
同时他们的隐私
learning.
也受到保护
All you have to do is to drag
你只需要将模型
and drop an ML model in Xcode
拖拽进 Xcode
and Core ML takes care of the
剩下的就看
rest.
Core ML 了
I think the big question remains
那么问题来了
is where do I get these models
这些机器学习模型
from?
从哪儿来呢
So last year, we provided you
去年 我们给大家提供了
two options.
两个选择
The first one was you could
第一个是
download some of these models,
你可以从我们网站上
popular models from our website
下载机器学习模型
but, more importantly, we also
但更重要的是
released Core ML tools.
我们还发布了 Core ML 工具
Core ML tools allow you to tap
有了 Core ML 工具
the work which is done by
你们就可以使用
amazing ML community.
了不起的 ML 社区创作作品了
So the idea is, again, simple.
方法也很简单
You choose your favorite
选择你最想要的学习资料库
learning library, train your
在该资料库中
model in that training library,
训练你的模型
convert it into Core ML from
将模型导入 Core ML
that and then just integrate it
然后再嵌入
into your app.
你的 App 即可
When we released Core ML, we
我们发布 Core ML 的时候
released with only five or six
Core ML 只支持
training libraries support for
五个或六个
five or six training library but
训练资料库
within a year, we have support
但是一年以内
for all the famous training
我们就支持了
libraries out there.
所有热门的资料库
We are enhancing our tools to
我们现在还在改良工具
even allow you more
让你们有更大
customization.
自定义的空间
And we are going to talk about
明天的会上
more about Core ML tools in
我们会给大家更详细介绍
tomorrow's session.
Core ML 工具
Another thing we did towards the
2017 年年底
end of the year, we released
我们发布了 Turi Create 这是我们的
machine learning library.
开源机器学习数据集
We are going to talk about Turi
明天的会议上我们也会
Create in tomorrow's session.
介绍 Turi Create
But this year, we want to give
今年 我们想给大家
you something even more.
带来一些新的东西
We want to continue our journey.
希望能继续我们的征途
We want to give you something
给大家带来一些原生的
native, something Swifty,
既灵活又基于 Swift 的东西
something that harnesses the
对 Xcode 的功能
power of our Xcode, something
好好加以利用
that puts the focus on you, our
将关注点放在你们身上
developers, something that just
开发人员身上
demystify machine learning for
让机器学习变得简单明了
Hence, we are introducing Create
这就是我们发布 Create ML 的原因
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
Our machine learning framework
下面说说我们基于 Swift 的
in Swift.
机器学习框架
So Create ML completes the
Create ML 让机器学习的
left-hand side of the equation.
组成部分变得完整
The idea is you make a model in
你可以在 Create ML 中
Create ML and you run it in Core
创建一个模型
ML.
然后在 Core ML 中运行该模型
You do complete end-to-end
这样你就可以用我们最喜欢的
machine learning in Swift, our
编程语言 Swift
favorite language.
从头到脚进行机器学习开发
So you are not dealing with
无需面对开发过程中
language oddities where you are
需要用到多种语言的情况
training in one language and
例如 你用一种语言训练模型
then running in, for instance,
而又在另一种语言中
another language.
运行模型
Create ML is simple and very
Create ML
powerful.
既简单又强大
It is tailored to your app.
为各位的 App 量身打造
It leverages core Apple
Create ML 运用了
technologies, and you do
Apple 核心技术
everything on your Mac.
在你的 Mac 上就能使用
So for this year we are going to
今年 目前为止
focus on three very important
我们的重点是
use cases.
三个非常重要的用例
The first one is images, second
第一个是图像
is text, and the third one is
第二个是文本
tabular data.
第三个是表格数据
These are the top use cases that
我们认为这三个用例
we believe will benefit you.
对大家是最有用的
So you can do things like custom
你可以自定义
image classifier.
图像分类器
Idea is that you make your own
这需要你自己创建
recognize product from your
对你产品列表中的产品
product catalog.
完成正确识别
You can do things like text
你也可以
classifier so you can make your
做文本分类器
own sentiment analysis, topic
然后自己做情感分析
analysis, domain analysis.
话题分析 或领域分析
And you can also do classical
你还可以
regression and classification on
对列表数据做
tabular data.
经典回归及分类
For example, let's just say you
举个例子 你可能想
want to predict the wine quality
根据红酒的化学成分
using its chemical composition.
预测红酒品质
The possibilities are endless,
这样的例子数不胜数
and we are going to discuss them
在接下来的三十分钟里
in detail in the next 30
我们来详细探讨一下
minutes.
这个状况
However, before we do, let's
在我们开始前
take a look at common workflow.
我们先看一下普通的工作流程
First, let's just say you are
假如你想
trying to enable an experience
在你的 App 中
in your app, make sure that
添加一个新的功能
machine learning is the right
首先确保机器学习
thing to do there.
是正确的选择
So don't just blindly apply
不要盲目地
machine learning.
使用机器学习
Make sure machine learning is
确保机器学习
the right thing to do there and
是适合你的
define a machine learning
然后明确
problem.
你要解决的问题
Second, collect data.
第二步是收集数据
Make sure this data reflects the
要保证你的数据可以反映
real usage of your app.
你 App 的真实使用情况
So, for example, if you're
例如 如果你在
making a custom image classifier
制作一个图像分类器
that is going to be used by
用户会在 iPhone 上
users on their iPhone, so
使用你的 App
collect pictures from your
那你就需要收集
iPhone.
iPhone 中的照片
Do not collect -- collect less
不要收集太多
screenshots but have more iPhone
屏幕截图 主要还是
pictures.
iPhone 的照片
Then you train your model.
下一步是训练模型
Finally, an important step here
最后一个重要步骤是
is to evaluate this model.
对你的模型进行评估
The model evaluation is done on
模型评估需要用
a separate handout set.
一组不一样的数据来检验
If you're happy, you write out
如果你觉得满意
the ML model.
就可以导出模型
But let's just say the results
不过我们假设结果
are not good.
并不令人满意
You should either retrain your
你要不就用不同的参数
model with different parameters
重新训练模型
or you collect more data.
要不就收集更多数据
Create ML actually helps you
Create ML 在工作流程的
across all four stages of this
四个阶段
workflow.
都能给你提供帮助
We have powerful in-built data
我们有强大的
[inaudible] utilities, data
内置数据版工具 数据源和数据表
will talk in the remainder of
那么接下来
the presentation.
我会给大家介绍
You can actually train your
你只需一行代码
model using only one line of
就可以训练你的机器学习模型
And the training is done
训练过程会根据你的硬件
hardware optimized.
做最优化处理
There are built-in evaluation
Create ML 还有内置评估标准
metrics, so you don't have to
这样你就不用
write your own precision and
自己写精确率 召回率
recall and confusion metrics
和混淆矩阵的计算了
Use them. And finally, when
用现成的就行
you're happy, just write out the
最后 你对结果满意了
model.
导出模型即可
Now we will take a deeper look
现在我们深入研究一下
in all three use cases: images,
三个用例
text, and tabular data.
图像 文本 和列表数据
So let's start with images.
首先是图像
And to do that, I will invite
下面有请 Lizi Ottens 上台
Lizi Ottens, Senior Engineer in
她是机器学习团队的
Machine Learning team.
一名高级工程师
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Gaurav.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Gaurav
Since enabling image-based
基于图像的功能
experiences are some of the most
是 App 功能中最强大
powerful and interactive ones
也最具交互性的功能之一
today we'll take a look at how
所以我们今天来看一下
to train custom image
如何训练自定义的
classification models.
图像分类模型
Image classification is the
图像分类是
problem of identifying what
在一组标签中
label out of a set of categories
找出你想要给某张图片
you'd like to apply to an image.
添加的标签
Depending on the type of
根据训练数据的不同
training data, you can target
你可以将目标定为
domain specific use cases to
在 App 中实现
enable in your apps.
特定领域的用例
The first step is to collect
我们的第一步是收集训练数据
In doing so, we'll take a look
让我们来看一个
at a fruit classifier and see
水果分类器是如何成型的
First, you'd want to gather many
首先 你需要收集很多
varied types of images that
不同类型的图像
reflect the true data that
这些图像要与你想得到的
you'll end up seeing and then
最终结果保持一致
label them.
然后给图像添加标签
First, you can do this as a
你可以先做一个图集
dictionary with the string label
图集的字符串标签
corresponding to arrays of
要与图集中的图像保持一致
Or what we've noticed is many
或者我们注意到
popular data sets are organized
很多热门的数据组
in hierarchical directory
是通过分层目录结构整理的
structures such that the label
也就是说 图像的标签
is the name of the folder that
就是图片文件夹的名字
contains all images within it.
文件夹中包含所有相关图片
There are also other data
还有一些其他数据源
sources such as single folders
比如 在单个文件夹里
that contain labeled filenames.
图片标签被添加到文件名称中
And in the Create ML API, we've
Create ML 的接口
provided conveniences to extract
便于提取
these structures.
这些不同结构
Now training is the more complex
下面是比较复杂的部分
part of the equation.
模型训练
So once you have your data, this
准备好数据后
is what you will get next.
就要训练模型了
And what you can do is you can
你可以通过
start training a very complex
输入的图像
model from scratch on your input
从零开始 训练一个复杂的模型
And for this you need lots and
这时你需要大量的标签数据
You need big compute and you
你还需要大量的计算
need a lot of patience.
和很好的耐心
But another well-established
在机器学习领域
technique in the industry is
另一个比较成功的技术
transfer learning.
就是迁移学习
And since Apple has lots of
由于 Apple 在训练
experience in training complex
复杂模型上
machine learning models, we
有丰富的经验
already have one in the
操作系统中
operating system that you can
已经包含一个
take advantage of.
你可以利用的模型了
So what we do is we apply
我们要做的是
transfer learning on top of this
将迁移学习用于
model that already exists in the
操作系统中的模型
OS, and we augment it,
然后对其进行补充
retraining the last few layers
用你准备的数据
to your specific data so you no
重新训练最后几个层次
longer need millions of images.
这样你就不用收集几百万张图片了
You can train a good classifier
只需用你能收集到的数据
using the amount of data that
就可以训练出一个不错的图像分类器
This results in faster training
这可以节省很多训练时间
And for developers that we've
我们看到很多开发人员
worked with, we've seen them go
一开始花费数小时训练模型
from hours of training down to
后来逐渐减少到几分钟
minutes for thousands of images
只需用几千张图像
or for small data sets, even
或更小的数据组就可以
seconds.
有些甚至几秒就能完成
This also results in much
这也缩减了模型大小
smaller models going from
从几百 MB
hundreds of megabytes down to
缩减至几 MB
thousands of images or even
只需几千张图片
kilobytes.
小的甚至有几 KB 的
The goal of Create ML is to
Create ML 的目标在于
abstract much of this and make
简化模型训练
it simple and easy to use.
让机器学习变得简单易用
But to prove it, let's take a
为了证明这一点
look at a demo.
我们来看一个例子
First, to set up the problem, I
首先 为了发现问题
started by running an app that's
我运行了一个 App
using a state-of-the-art image
而这个 App
classification model that's
采用的是行业现有的
already in the industry.
一个图像分类模型
This one, though, is quite
这个模型是挺大的
large.
在 App 中有 100 MB
And if we run it, we have some
我们运行 App
fruits but it's not quite what I
可以得到一些水果的图片
was looking for.
但是这不是我想要的结果
I'd really like it if, instead,
如果我们能将
we could classify these
这些特例分类就更棒了
So what we can do is we can
我们可以
switch to a new playground and
新建一个 Playground
import CreateMLUI and walk
输入 CreateMLUI
through how to do this using the
我借助 UI 给大家演示
UI for it.
如何操作
We can define a builder.
我们定义一个创建器
Initialize it.
设为启动
And to enable drag-and-drop
然后启用拖拽式训练
training, we can show the
我们可以
builder in the live view.
实时展示创建器
This brings up a prompt in the
这会在实时视图中
live view to drag in images to
出现拖拽添加图像的提示
begin training.
添加后开始训练模型
And here I set aside some photos
我准备了一些
of fruits.
水果的图片 有蓝莓 还有其他的水果
And you can drag them in and
你可以将图片拖进来
automatically an image
然后你的 Mac
classifier model begins training
就自动开始训练
on the Mac.
图像分类模型了
All of this is accelerated by
无论有多少类别
the GPU on however many
你的 GPU 都会加速训练进程
It automatically tells you what
Create ML 会自动展示
the accuracy is on the training
训练数据组的准确率 然而
helpful is to try this on new
更有效的是
images that the model hasn't
用模型未识别过的图像
seen before to predict how it
来预测实际用例中
will do on real use cases.
模型的性能
So I can drag in this other
我将另一个包含新图片的文件夹拖入
And now the model is evaluating
现在 模型在评估新的水果图片
And if you scroll, you can see
往下滑可以
what the true label is of each
看到图片的真实标签
type as well as with the
和模型预测出的标签
And if you're happy with this
如果你对准确度
accuracy, what you can do is you
还算满意
can take the model and drag it
你就可以将模型
into your app.
拖入你的 App
I'll add it here.
我加在了这里
And if we take a look, this
我们现在再来看
model is 83 kilobytes.
这个模型只有 83 KB
It's a huge savings down from
比之前的模型
hundreds.
小了很多
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
So we can delete the old model
我们可以删除
that we were using before.
之前的旧模型
And in the view controller, we
在视图控制器中
can initialize this new one,
我们可以启用新的模型
ImageClassifier.
ImageClassifier
We can then re-run the app,
我们重新运行 App
bring up the simulator, and see
打开模拟器
how it does on some of those
看一下新模型
fruits.
对于水果图片的识别
On the raspberry, it can now
现在 App 可以
correctly predict it since we
正确识别覆盆子了
trained the model to recognize
因为我们训练了模型
raspberries.
对于覆盆子的识别
We can even see if it can
我们甚至可以看看
distinguish from strawberries
模型是否能区分草莓和覆盆子
and it can now.
现在能做到了
But there are other workflows
然而你还可以采用
you can use.
其他的工作流程
Perhaps you want to do this
或许你想
programmatically or perhaps you
用编程控制
want to automate it.
或自动训练
We can also walk through how to
下面就来讲一下我们
use Create ML to do so.
如何在 Create ML 中实现
So now we can switch to another
我们切换到新的 Playground
playground and import Create ML.
然后输入 CreateML
Since we'll be using URLs, we
由于会用到 URL
also can import foundation.
我们也输入 Foundation
And since, on our desktop, we
因为桌面上
still have these folders of
还有水果图片的文件夹
fruits, we can say where they
我们可以直接输入路径
are and also say where the
测试用的图片
testing fruits are.
也是一样
And then the next step is to
下一步是
actually train the model.
训练模型
So we can define a model, and we
我们可以定义一个模型
can initialize an image
然后启动一个
classifier.
图像分类器
And now if we take a look at
现在 我们看一下
what auto complete shows to us,
自动完成的情况
we can see we can provide
我们提供多个标签
training data in the form of a
和多张图像所匹配的
dictionary of labels to arrays
训练数据
of images or we can use a data
或者使用数据源
training parameters if we want
甚至可以用
to.
模型训练的参数
Let's use a data source.
我们用一个数据源吧
And we'll use label directories
我们用 labeledDirectories
since that's how our data is
因为我们的数据
organized and specify the
是根据标签目录整理的
training directory.
然后指定 trainingDirectory
And since we're running in the
由于我们在 Xcode Playground
new [inaudible] mode of Xcode
新的 REPL 模式下
playground, I just need to hit
运行模型
shift enter and the model begins
我只需按 Shift + Enter
training right away.
模型马上就开始训练了
You can even pull up the console
你可以将控制台
and see output of one, its
打开查看
extracting features and how many
提取功能
iterations it's running through.
并查看有多少重复
Afterwards, you can also open
之后 你也可以
quick looks and see the name of
打开 Quick Look
the model and how many instances
查看模型的名称
it's trained on.
和经过多少数据的训练
Now we might want to evaluate on
现在我们用测试数据
aside.
评估一下模型
So what we can do is we can call
我们可以
evaluation on another data
对另一个数据源
source since that folder is
调用估算
organized the same way,
因为整理方法与之前相同
specifying the URL of the
明确测试数据的 URL
You can hit shift enter and now
点击 Shift + Enter
the model is evaluating testing
模型就开始评估
images.
测试图像了
Once it's complete, we can also
评估结束后
look at the quick look and see
我们可以查看 Quick Look
how many examples it evaluated
看评估了多少数据
on as well as how many classes
文件夹中包含
were in that folder altogether
多少类别
and the accuracy.
和模型准确率
If we're happy with that, we can
如果多结果满意
write it out.
就可以将模型导出
And say that I want to write it
假设我想
to the desktop with the name
导出到桌面
fruit classifier ML model.
并命名为 FruitClassifier
Once I do, you can see this new
成功之后
model appears on the desktop.
桌面上就有这个新模型了
We can double-click it and take
我们双击模型查看
a look and see it's exactly the
可以发现
same.
大小完全没变
This is also 83 kilobytes.
还是 83 KB
Furthermore, we can integrate it
此外 我们可以以同样的方式
back into our app the same way.
将模型嵌入我们的 App
Let's recap.
让我们重温一下
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
We saw two ways of training
我们看到两种
image classifier models in
在 Create ML 中
Create ML.
训练图像分类器模型的方式
One was with the UI which makes
一是借助 UI
it super simple to drag-and-drop
拖拽训练数据
your training data and
及评估数据
evaluation data to produce an ML
这样创建模型
model.
非常简单
The other way was with the
二是利用 Create ML 接口
If we walk through some of this
看代码的话
code, we can see the first thing
我们会发现
we had to do was import Create
我们首先需要输入 CreateML
The next was to specify where
下一步要明确
our training and testing data
训练数据和测试数据的位置
was and then actually begin
然后通过明确
training the model by specifying
测试数据的结构
how our training data was laid
我们就可以开始训练模型了
We can then evaluate on the
然后我们用测试数据
testing data and finally save ML
评估模型
model.
最后保存模型
If you want to automate this,
如果想自动操作
you can also turn these into
你可以将这些
scripts, which is a very popular
写成脚本
way of saving what you've done
很多人用脚本保存操作过程
and re-running it whenever.
并且可以随时运行
You can then change permissions
你可以更改
on the file and run them like
文件的权限
so.
然后就这样运行
Or for other workflows, you can
对于其他的工作流程
always use Swift command line
你可以使用
[inaudible].
Swift 命令行
So we've seen today how to train
今天我们了解了
image classification models
如何通过不同的工作流程
using a few different workflows.
训练图像分类模型
But next, I'd like to pass it
下面我要有请 Tao
off to Tao to talk about natural
来讲一下
language.
自然语言处理
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Lizi.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Lizi
Hello everyone.
大家好
My name is Tao.
我的名字是 Tao
I'm an engineer here at Apple
我是 Apple Core ML 团队的
working on the Core ML team.
一名工程师
You just saw how easy and
刚刚大家看到了
intuitive to train an image
我们用几行代码
classifier with just a few lines
就可以简单且直观地
of code.
训练图像分类器
Now I'm going to show you the
自然语言也可以做到
same can be done for natural
下面由我
language.
为大家讲解
In this year's release, we're
今年发布的 Create ML 中
going to support two natural
我们会支持两种自然语言处理
language tasks: text
文本分类
classification and word tagging.
和词语标注
Today, I'm going to focus on
今天 我会重点介绍
text classification.
文本分类
For details on word tagging,
想了解词语标注的更多细节
please join the natural language
请各位参加明天
session that happens tomorrow.
自然语言方面的会议
Text classification can be used
文本分类
in a few machine learning
在机器学习中
applications.
有几种 App
For example, sentiment analysis.
例如 情感分析
The energy of developers is
各位开发人员的热情
amazing.
不可抵挡
That's a positive note.
这是正面信息
You want your app to know it.
你希望你的 App 可以识别
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
Spam analysis.
垃圾邮件分析
If you saw this message in your
如果你在邮箱中
mailbox, you know it's very
看到这条信息
likely it's spam.
你知道这是垃圾邮件
So you want your app to know
所以你希望你的 App
that as well.
也能识别
Topic analysis.
话题分析
The Warriors just had an amazing
勇士队翻盘
comeback win.
大获全胜
That's a sport post.
这是一条体育新闻
You want your app to be able to
你希望你的 App
classify that.
能划分类别
So to train such a classifier,
想要训练这样的分类器
the first thing you do is to
你首先要收集
collect some training data.
一些训练数据
With Create ML, we support a few
Create ML 支持
different ways for you to
多种整理训练
organize your training data.
数据的方式
For example, label directories.
比如 标签目录
Here you have two folders.
这里有两个文件夹
One named positive, the other
一个叫正面
one named negative.
一个叫负面
Within each folder, you have a
每个文件夹中
number of articles with just raw
都有一些原始文本
text whose truth label is simply
它们的准确标签
the name of the folder.
就是文件夹的名字
Alternatively, you can prepare
或者你可以
your training data using simple
在 CSV 文件中
CSV where you prepare your raw
记录原始文本
text and the truth label
和准确标签
separated by comma.
以逗号隔开
We also support JSON formatting
我们还支持 JSON 格式的
the training data and know that
训练数据
we just talk about the training
我们刚提到
data organization and you can
训练数据整理
actually organize your test data
测试数据也可以用
in the exact same way.
同样的方式整理
Now with your training data and
训练数据和测试数据
test data ready, what other
都准备好后
steps involve to train such a
训练文本分类器
text classifier?
还需要什么步骤呢
A typical workflow would look
典型的工作流程
something like this.
大概是这样
You start with your raw text.
我们从原始文本入手
You do a language identification
通过语言识别
to figure out which language it
确认原始文本的语言
You convert that into tokens.
将文本转换成标记
And then you convert that into
再将标记
some feature values and then you
转换成相应特征值
can apply a machine learning
然后加入机器学习模型
model that gives you some
输出一些预测值
to map to some desired label.
再将预测值转成标签
And then you can compare that
然后你可以将标签
label to your truth label and
与准确标签对比
start iterating on it.
不断重复这样的过程
With Create ML, though, we took
然而有了 Create ML
away all these complexities so
整个流程变得简单
that all you need to do is to
这样你只需
prepare raw text with their
准备原始文本
truth label and start training
和准确标签
immediately.
再训练模型就可以了
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
Now let me give you a concrete
下面我来给大家展示
example like how you can train
如何训练文本分类器
such a classifier and use it.
并对其加以使用
For example, we have this simple
假如我们有一个简单的 App
app called Stay Positive whose
叫做保持正面
purpose is to encourage positive
App 的目的是为了激发
post.
正面的帖子
If a user entered I hate
如果有用户输入
traffic, the background turns
我讨厌堵车
red and it will disable the post
则帖子背景变为红色
button.
发帖按钮变为不可点击
I love driving my car at five
我喜欢淡定地在车流中
mile per hour just chilling in
以每小时 10 公里的速度
traffic.
向前行驶
That's a positive post.
这是个正面的帖子
We encourage you to post it.
我们鼓励这种帖子
Just imagine what our Internet
如果每个人的手机上
would look like with this app
都装了这个 App
running on everybody's phone?
互联网会变得多好呀
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
Now, in order to do that, let me
想要实现这一点
give you a live demo.
我来给大家做个演示
So to train such a classifier,
要训练这样一个分类器
the first thing I do is collect
我们首先要
some training data.
收集训练数据
On my desktop, I have a train
在桌面上 有一个训练数据文件夹
folder and also a test folder.
和一个测试数据文件夹
In train folder, we have two
在训练文件里
folders.
我们有两个文件夹
One is named positive, the other
一个命名为正面
one negative, and there are a
另一个为负面
number of articles in each
每个文件夹中
folder.
有一些文章
And test folder is organized in
测试文件夹的整理方式
a very similar way.
基本相同
So the first thing I do is to
首先 我需要
import Create ML.
输入 CreateML
Now I need to tell the
现在 我需要明确
[inaudible] where to find my
训练数据的位置
For that, I'm simply using a URL
我用的只是 URL
capability and then I can start
然后我就可以
training my model using the
用 Lizi 展示过的
label directories that Lizi just
标签目录
showed you.
来训练我的模型了
Look. The training has started.
看 训练开始了
As you can see on the bottom
从底下可以看到
there, there is some progress
在这里有进度报告
Looks like training has
训练好像已经结束了
finished.
现在你可以
performance numbers on this
查看这个模型中
model.
的一些表现数据
For example,
例如 model.trainingMetrics
you this model has been trained
在训练中
on over 2000 examples and
使用了 2000 多个数据
accuracy is 100%.
准确率 100%
But how does it perform on some
那如果是新数据
unseen data?
这个模型表现会如何呢
So I'm going to do the same to
我接下来要
define test data and then
定义测试数据
evaluate that model on the test
然后用测试数据
data.
评估模型
As you can see, we have 77 test
可以看到
examples, and we are achieving
这里有 77 个测试数据
over 94% accuracy, which is very
准确率 94%
good.
效果非常好
I'm sure you want to iterate on
为了更高的准确率
that if you want to see like
你们可能想多训练几次
even a higher number, but this
但是这个数字
number is pretty good enough for
已经很好了
my app so let me just test it
所以下面我想
out.
试验一下
So to save out the model, what I
想要保存模型
need to do is define a URL where
我需要定义
it's saving to and then write
保存路径
out a model to my desktop.
然后将模型导出到桌面
Looks, that model has been
这看起来
saved.
模型已经保存了
So now I need to switch back to
现在切换到
my app.
我的 App 来
Just drag and drop it.
将模型拖拽过来
There you go.
这就可以了
Now I can start use it.
现在我就可以使用模型了
I will do let model equal to
let model = TextClassifier
textClassifier which should auto
它应当会自动填充
And then I'm going to insert
然后我要插入一些
some basic inference code.
基本的推理代码
In this inference code, as you
在这个推理代码中
see, the first line I do is
我在第一行使用了
using model.prediction to get
model.prediction
prediction.
来获取预测
And then in order to hook up
为了与 App
with this simple app UI, I just
简洁的 UI 兼容
convert that into some double
我将预测结果转换成两个值
Let's give it a try.
我们来试试
Yeah. Let's try some example we
先试一下
have showed you.
已经展示过的例子
I hate traffic.
我讨厌堵车 负面情绪
Negative. I love driving my car
我喜欢淡定地在车流中
at five mile per hour just
以每小时 10 公里的速度
chilling in traffic.
向前行驶
Positive. Let's try something
正面情绪 让我们尝试
different that'll be fun.
一些不一样的
Machine learning is hard.
机器学习很难
Create ML makes it so easy.
Create ML 让机器学习变得简单
Positive.
出现正面
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
So that's how you train your
这就是如何训练
customized text classifier and
你的文本分类器
drag it into your app to use it.
将其拖入 App 中并使用
Here's a recap.
我们来回顾一下
So to train such a classifier,
训练这样一个分类器
the first thing you do is to
首先你要
specify your data.
确定数据
You specify your training data
训练数据
as well as your test data and
以及测试数据
then you can create your model
然后用训练数据
on the training data.
创建模型
To evaluate its performance, you
评估模型性能时
evaluate a model on the test
用测试数据
data.
进行评估
Finally, to use your model in
最后 你只需用 write 接口
your app, you simply save it out
保存模型
using this write API.
就可以嵌入 App 中使用了
To summarize, with just a few
总的来说
lines of code, you can train
只需几行代码
your customized text classifier
你就可以训练自己的
simple intuitive.
文本分类器 简单又直观
With that, I'd like to hand back
下面 我将话筒
to Gaurav who is going to talk
转回给 Gaurav
about tabular data.
由他来介绍列表数据
Thank you.
谢谢各位
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Tao.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Tao
Besides images and text, another
除了图像和文本
common source of data that
另一类在解决
occurs very frequently when
机器学习问题时
you're solving a machine
很常见的数据来源
data.
就是列表数据
What I mean by tabular data, I
列表数据是指
mean the data is in special
有特殊格式
format or in a table format.
或列表形式的数据
This kind of data occurs fairly
这类数据非常常见
For example, let's just say
举个例子 假如
you're trying to predict house
你想利用床的数量
prices using number of beds,
浴室数量
number of baths, or square
或建筑面积
footage.
预测房价
Generally the data is arranged
这样的数据通常
in a tabular format.
是以列表形式整理的
You want to predict the quality
你想通过
of wine using its chemical
红酒中的化学成分
compositions.
预测红酒质量
Chances are data will be
你的数据有很大可能
arranged in table format.
是列表形式
Or something even simple like
或者一些简单的事
where to hop, which bar to hop
比如用酒吧减价时段
tonight using happy hour or its
或酒吧消费水平
price, the data will be in
决定今晚去哪家酒吧
tabular format.
你的数据会是列表形式
To handle the data which is in
要处理列表形式的数据
tabular format, we actually
我们需要用到
introduce a new data structure
一种新的数据结构
which we call as MLDataTable.
我们把它叫作 MLDataTable
MLDataTable is based on
MLDataTable 是基于
[inaudible] technology that we
Turi Create 的一项技术
will discuss in detail tomorrow.
我们明天会详细介绍
There's something interesting
这些数据表格
about these data tables.
有一点很有意思
The rows contains the
每一行包含
observations or examples.
一个例子的所有数据
So here, house number two has
这里二号房子
four bed, three bath, and 500K
有四张床 三间浴室
price.
价格是 50 万美元
The columns contains what we
每一列数据包含
call as features.
一种特征
So the beds are features, baths
床的数量 浴室数量
are features, square feet,
建筑面积等等
etcetera are features.
都是特征
There is one special column that
我们想预测的
we want to predict, in this case
是一列特殊的数据
price, and this column is known
那就是房屋价格
as target or response variable.
所以这一列是目标或反应变量
The whole idea behind tabular
列表数据处理
data is that we want to predict
其实是将目标变量
target variable as a function of
作为所有特征的函数
one or many of these features.
然后进行预测
So what are the common sources
那我们都支持
that we support?
什么格式的列表数据呢
Well, CSV, JSON as well as you
CSV JSON
can actually have code.
还有代码
So let's talk a little bit more
我们再谈谈
about MLDataTable.
MLDataTable
First, you can read data simply
你只需用 CSV
by using CSV.
数据可以轻松读取
What is more important that you
更重要的是
can access the column using a
你可以用下标标注
subscript notation.
访问数据列
So all you do is house or the
你只需调用
price and you get an entire
houseData[“price”]
column of price.
就可以得到整列价格数据
You can add two columns,
你可以对两列数据
two column, divide two columns.
做加减乘除
And the way you do it is in very
实现该操作的语句
natural looking syntax.
非常直观
So you just simply say house or
你只需要
the price divided by house or
用 houseData[“price”]
the square foot to get price per
除以 houseData[“sqft”]
square foot.
就得到每平方英尺的价格
Behind the scenes, this
在后台运行中
calculation is done using
计算通过
[inaudible] evaluation and
惰性求值
through vector operations.
和矢量运算完成
It can also do some of the other
还有一些其他
interesting things.
有意思的地方
For example, you can split data
例如你可以在训练中
table in training as well as you
切分数据表格
can even do filtering.
也可以过滤数据
So for example, if you're only
举个例子
interested in large houses, you
如果你只对大房子感兴趣
can create an indicator variable
就可以创建一个指示变量
and filter it out.
然后进行过滤
There a lot of operations that
列表数据支持
data table support.
很多种操作
I urge you to try it out in
希望大家可以在 Xcode
Xcode playground.
Playground 中多多尝试
They're fun.
非常有意思
Now once you have data in data
现在 当你将数据
table, you would like to do the
添进表格后
training on it.
就可以开始训练了
Create ML supports a large
Create ML 支持
number of algorithms such as
很多种算法
Boosted Tree Regression, Random
例如 提升树算法
Forest, etcetera.
随机森林回归算法 等等
And all of these algorithms are
这些算法
represented by their class.
有各自的级
In order to train your model,
想要训练模型
you only have to write one line
你只需要一行代码
Basically, you tell what is the
就是说 你只要
target and where you're getting
指定目标
the data and which is the
明确数据位置
algorithm you are instantiating.
指定算法 就可以了
So in this case, let's just say
在示例中 假设我们采用线性回归
Regression or Regularized Linear
或普通线性回归算法
Regression, you just actually
你只需要
tell it that the data is house
说明数据来自 houseData
data and the column is price.
以及数据列是 price
If you do Boosted Tree
如果选择 BoostedTreeRegression
Regression, just replace Linear
就将线性回归算法
Regression with Boosted Tree and
替换掉就可以了
Now Random Forest like that.
RandomForest 是这个
Plus we also provide a high
我们还提供
level abstraction MLRegressor
高度提炼过的 MLRegressor
that automatically runs all
它可以自动运行
these algorithms and choose the
所有的算法
best one for you.
并为你找出最合适的
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］
This is in line with our
这与我们的理念相吻合
philosophy that you should focus
我们希望大家
on task.
可以将精力用于其他任务
So the task is to predict the
示例中的任务就是
price.
预测房屋价格
You should not focus about
你们不应当
nitty-gritty details of the
花太多精力在算法的细节上
Having said that, in case you're
如果你是算法方面的专家
an expert, you can actually use
你也可以使用
Boosted Tree and change its
BoostedTree
parameters also.
并自己修改其中的参数
So a complete end-to-end would
一个完整的开发流程
look like this.
就是这样的
It follows exactly the same
跟图像和文本的
pattern as image and text.
流程一模一样
First, you specify the data.
首先是指定数据
Second, you just create your
第二点是
model.
创建自己的模型
Third, you evaluate the model.
第三 评估模型
And once you're happy, you save
一旦你感到满意就
it out.
保存模型
So tabular data, image data, or
列表数据 图像数据
text data, they all follow the
文本数据的
same pattern.
流程都是一样的
So let's just take a quick
现在让我们
summary of what we saw in this
快速回忆一下
session.
本次会议的内容
So Create ML is our ML framework
Create ML 是我们机器学习框架的新工具
insert.
它简单易用
is very powerful and it
功能强大
leverages core Apple
它搭载了 Apple 的核心技术
You do end-to-end machine
你可以在 Mac 上用 Swift
learning in Swift on your Mac.
完整运用机器学习
We also discussed about our
我们还说到
workflow.
工作流程
Once again, you start from an
你需要从功能入手
What is the experience you're
你想要实现什么样的功能
Then define the problem.
然后发现问题
Then collect the data.
收集数据
Make sure this data is
要保证你的数据可以反映
usage of your scenario.
真实的使用场景
Then you train the model.
然后训练模型
And finally evaluate it.
最后评估模型
And once you are happy, you just
满意之后
save it out.
保存模型
Create ML is in Swift.
Create ML 基于 Swift 语言
And it's available on macOS
在 macOS Mojave 中已经可以使用
You can use it in Xcode
你可以在 Xcode Playground
Playground, Swift Scripts and
Swift Scripts
[inaudible].
及 Swift REPL 中使用
So please try it out.
大家多多尝试
We would love to hear from you.
我们很期待大家的反馈
We are here to receive your
我们会收集反馈
feedback, and we hope that you
希望你们也同样
will love it as much as we do.
喜爱 Create ML
We will be in the machine
我们之后还有
learning get together as well as
机器学习的聚会
the labs.
以及实验室议程
So there is -- tomorrow there is
明天也有一个聚会
We will be in labs also, so
我们也会在实验室
please give us your feedback.
希望届时能得到大家的反馈
There are also related sessions
在 WWDC 的 App 中
in the WWDC App.
有相关的会议信息
We have Core ML session tomorrow
明天上午有 Core ML 的会议
morning and ML session tomorrow
下午是机器学习的会议
afternoon, Vision sessions on
周四有一个
Thursday.
视觉内容的会议
And we have labs on Wednesday
在周三和周五 我们有实验室议程
Thank you.
感谢大家
[ Applause ]
［ 掌声 ］